A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Finance, 1992; 1994; 2000-2018 (bulk 2013-2017)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Finance, 1992; 1994; 2000-2018 (bulk 2013-2017)
The Library of Virginia
52169
20.84 cubic feet (30 Boxes)
Virginia Secretary of Finance
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78 and 2.2-3808.1. Restricted documents have been sealed within the collection. Types of records restricted include, but are not limited to: attorney-client privilege, mediation and settlement discussions, and bank account numbers.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Virginia Secretary of Finance on 8 January 2018.
Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties. Compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governors top management team or "secretariats," as they are called now. The General Assembly in 1972 created six Secretariats positions initially. As government reorganized, that number fluctuated when government agencies expanded or consolidated.
Since the establishment of a secretarial system in 1972, there have been several reorganizations of that system. The financial management function of the state has shifted from under the direction of the Secretary of Finance to the Secretary of Administration; then to Secretary of Administration and Finance and currently back to the Secretary of Finance, through various reorganizations of state government from 1970's to the present. The function of the secretary is to provide sound fiscal management and recommend to the Governor a comprehensive budget for those agencies under his jurisdiction. The secretary's responsibilities are: to monitor programs, services and performance of subordinate state agencies to develop state policies programs for long-range planning and policy formulation; and approve solicitation or acceptance of any donations, gifts or grants; to hold agency heads accountable for their agency's administrative, fiscal and program performance. All secretaries are appointed by the governor and serve at his will.
Governor Terry McAuliffe (2014-2018) reappointed Richard "Ric" D. Brown to serve as Secretary of Finance. Richard Brown was appointed as Secretary of Finance by Governor Timothy Kaine in 2008, reappointed by Governor Robert McDonnell in 2010, and continued to serve until he retired in 2018. Prior to his appointment as Secretary of Finance, Brown worked in the Virginia Department of Planning and budget beginning in 1971. He served as agency head from 2001 to 2008.
Scope and Content
Records, 1992, 1994, 2000-2018, of Secretary of Finance Richard "Ric" D. Brown during the administrations of Governor Tim M. Kaine (2006-2010), Governor Robert F. McDonnell (2010-2014) and Terry McAuliffe (2014-2018). The collection is housed in 30 boxes and includes budget and financial presentations, decision briefs, revenue reports, correspondence, and Secretary of Finance department subject files. Information on the state budget, revenue forecasting, Virginia's bond rating, and Medicaid expansion can be found throughout the collection. Also included are records from Brown's tenure at the Virginia Department of Planning and Budget.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files: Secretariat, 2006; 2008-2018
Series II. Bond Rating, 1992; 1994; 2000-2017
Series III. Decision Briefs, 2014-2017
Series IV. Joint Money Committee Meetings Files, 2005; 2007-2014; 2016-2017
Series V. Planning and Budget Files, 2004-2006; 2013-2017
Series VI. Public Relations-Presentations, 2008; 2008; 2010; 2013-2014; 2017
Series VII. Special Projects and Studies, 2012; 2014; 2016-2017.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files: Secretariat, 2006; 2008-2018., Extent: 4 boxes (4.0 cu. ft.). (Box 1-4)
  Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 2006, 2008-2018, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance Ric Brown, during multiple gubernatorial administrations, is housed in 4 record center boxes. This series documents communication and subject matter with boards and committees that the secretary was a member of: Virginia Tobacco Commission (VTC)/Virginia Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission (VTRRC), Virginia Research Investment Committee (VRIC) and Virginia Growth and Opportunity Board (GO Virginia). This series includes agendas, correspondence, handouts, memorandums, minutes, email and reports.
  - Boards and Committees
    - Virginia Tobacco Commission (VTC)/Virginia Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission (VTRRC), 2006, 2008-2017.
      In 1998, the Attorneys General of 46 states signed the Master Settlement Agreement (MSA) with the four largest tobacco companies in the United States to settle state suits and recover billions of dollars in costs associated with treating smoking-related illnesses. The Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission is a 28-member body created by the 1999 General Assembly. Its mission is the promotion of economic growth and development in formerly tobacco-dependent communities, using proceeds of the national tobacco settlement. To date, the Commission has created tens of thousands of jobs and hundreds of millions of dollars of investment in Southern and Southwest Virginia. Originally called the Virginia Tobacco Commission, the name was changed in 2016. Source: website of the Commission, https://revitalizeva.org/ (accessed 19 July 2024). Originally called the Virginia Tobacco Commission, the name was changed in 2015.
      Chronological
      - Virginia Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Commission, Briefing Book, 2006. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and handouts, 2008. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2009 Jan 13. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2009 Apr 23. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2009 July 29-30. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2009 Oct 28-29. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 2009. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2010 Jan 11-12. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2010 Apr 28-29. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2010 July 28-29. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - VTC, Southwest Economic Development and Special Projects Committees Meeting, 2010 Oct 4. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2010 Oct 27-28. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence and Reports, 2010 Nov 2. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - VTC, Special Projects Committee Meeting, 2010 Dec 14. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2011 Jan 10-11. (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2011 May 25-26. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - JLARC, Review of the Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Commission, 2011 June. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - VTC, Special Projects Committee Meeting (1 of 3), 2011 Sept 15. (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - VTC, Special Projects Committee Meeting (2 of 3), 2011 Sept 15. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - VTC, Special Projects Committee Meeting (3 of 3), 2011 Sept 15. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2011 Sept 28-29. (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2012 Jan 9-10. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2012 May 23-24. (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2012 Sept 26-27. (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2013 Jan 7-8. (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2013 May 22-23. (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence, 2013. (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2013 Sept 25-26. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2014 Jan 6-7. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 2014 Mar. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2014 May 21-22. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2014 Sept 24-25. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2015 Jan 12-13. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Tobacco Commission Meeting, 2015 May 20-21. (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission (VTRRC) Meeting, 2015 Sept 22-23. (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Virginia Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission Meeting, 2016 Jan 11-12. (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Virginia Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission Meeting, 2016 May 23-24. (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 2016 June-Aug. (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Virginia Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission Meeting, 2016 Sept 19-20. (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Virginia Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission Meeting, 2017 Jan 9-10. (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 2017. (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Virginia Tobacco Region Revitalization Commission Meeting, 2017 May 17-18. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Research Investment Committee (VRIC), 2015-2018.
      The Virginia Research Investment Committee (VRIC) and the Virginia Research Investment Fund were established by the General Assembly in 2016 as a part of the GO Virginia Initiative. To position the Commonwealth as a national leader in science-based and technology-based research, VRIC makes investments in innovative and collaborative research, development, and commercialization projects and programs from Virginia’s public colleges and universities that have a high potential for economic development and job creation opportunities. Source: website GO Virginia, https://govirginia.org/initiatives/research-and-innovation/ (accessed 19 July 2024).
      - Correspondence and Handouts, 2015. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Commonwealth Health Research Board (CHRB) Meeting, 2015 May 11. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting, 2016 May 23. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, 2016 June-Oct. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting, 2016 Oct 12. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, 2016 Oct-Nov. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting, 2016 Dec 5. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence, 2016 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting, 2017 Mar 14. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting, 2017 Apr 6. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting (1 of 2), 2017 May 19. (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting (2 of 2), 2017 May 19. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting (1 of 2), 2017 May 24. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting (2 of 2), 2017 May 24. (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence, 2017 Apr-Aug. (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting, 2017 Aug 24. (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting (1 of 2), 2017 Oct 9. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting (2 of 2), 2017 Oct 9. (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting, 2017 Nov 7. (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Virginia Research Investment Committee Meeting, 2017 Dec 11. (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Correspondence, 2018 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Virginia Economic Development Partnership, 2006, 2008-2017.
      The Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP) is the state economic development authority for the Commonwealth of Virginia. Created in 1995, VEDP collaborates with local, regional, and state partners to encourage the expansion and diversification of Virginia’s economy. VEDP works to accomplish these objectives through a variety of activities, including marketing and lead generation; business retention, expansion, and attraction; trade development; business intelligence; competitive benchmarking; site development; performance-based incentives; and talent solutions. Source: website of the Virginia Economic Development Partnership, https://www.vedp.org/(accessed 19 July 2024).
      - Virginia Economic Development Partnership Proposed Operating Plan for the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 2007 (Draft), 2006 June 2. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Auditor of Public Accounts, Report on Audit of Virginia Economic Development Partnership for the Year Ended 30 June 2008, 2008. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2008 Sept 11. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Genworth, 2008 Oct-Nov. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2008 Dec 11. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 2009 Jan-Feb. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2009 Mar 10. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 2009 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2009 June 18. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 2009 June-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2009 Sept 10. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 2009 Sept-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2009 Dec 10. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2010 Mar 11. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 2010 Apr-May. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2010 June 10. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2010 Sept 9. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2010 Dec 9. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Presentation to Senate Finance Subcommittee on Economic Development and Natural Resources, 2011 Feb 1. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2011 Mar 10. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2011 June 16. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2011 Sept 8. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - VEDP Annual Report, 2011 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2011 Dec 8. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2012 Mar 15. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2012 June 27. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2012 Sept 13. (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2012 Dec 13. (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2013 Mar 14. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2013 June 13. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2013 Sept 12. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2014 Mar 12. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Governor's Opportunity Fund transactions for FY 2014, 2014 July. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - VEDP, Major Employment and Investment (MEI) Project Approval Commission Meeting, 2014 Aug 15. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - VEDP Return on Investment (ROI) Meeting, 2015 Aug 12. (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2015 Sept 10. (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - VEDP Funding, 2015 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Virginia Sustained Growth Study, 2016 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, 2016 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - VEDP Executive Committee Meeting, 2016 Apr 13. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - VEDP Finance and Auditing Committee Meeting, 2016 Apr 13. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, 2016 May. (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - VEDP Executive Committee Meeting, 2016 May 27. (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - VEDP Executive Committee Meeting, 2016 June 8. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - VEDP Finance and Auditing Committee Meeting, 2016 June 8. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2016 June 9. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - VEDP, Major Employment and Investment (MEI) Project Approval Commission Meeting, 2016 July 11. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 2016 Aug. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2016 Sept 8. (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - VEDP Finance and Auditing Committee Meeting, 2016 Sept 8. (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - VEDP Regional Visits and Listening Tour, Final Report, 2016 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - VEDP Board of Directors' Meeting, 2016 Dec 8. (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, 2016 Nov-Dec; 2017 Feb; undated. (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - VEDP CEO Search Process (1 of 5), 2016 May. (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - VEDP CEO Search Process (2 of 5), 2016 May. (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - VEDP CEO Search Process (3 of 5), 2016 June; 2016 Sept. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - VEDP CEO Search Process (4 of 5), 2016 Sept-Oct. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - VEDP CEO Search Process (5 of 5), 2016 Oct-Nov. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Growth and Opportunity Board (GO Virginia), 2014-2017.
      GO Virginia is an initiative by Virginia’s senior business leaders to foster private-sector growth and job creation through state incentives for regional collaboration by business, education, and government. GO Virginia Coalition launched in July 2015 by Virginia's senior business leadership with broad bipartisan support. These records document the creation of GO Virginia. Source: website of GO Virginia, https://govirginia.org/(accessed 19 July 2024).
      - Correspondence, 2014. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 2015 May-July. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 2015 July. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 2015 Aug; 2015 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 2015 Nov-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence and Meeting Documents, 2016 Jan-Mar. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence and Meeting Documents, 2016 Apr-Oct. (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence and Meeting Documents, 2016 Oct-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Virginia DHCD Go Virginia Presentation to Senate Finance Committee, 2017 Jan 17. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - GO Virginia Board Meeting, 2017 Mar 14. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - GO Virginia Board Meeting, 2017 Apr 6. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - GO Virginia Orientation, 2017 Apr 20. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - GO Virginia Stakeholder Workgroup Meeting, 2017 May 16. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - GO Virginia Executive Committee Meeting, 2017 June 6. (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - GO Virginia Board Meeting, 2017 June 13. (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - GO Virginia Executive Committee Meeting, 2017 Aug 31. (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - GO Virginia Board Meeting, 2017 Sept 12. (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - GO Virginia Board Meeting, 2017 Oct 16. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series II. Bond Rating, 1992; 1994; 2000-2017., Extent: 3 boxes (1.70 cu. ft.). (Box 5-7)
  Series II. Bond Rating, 1992; 1994; 2000-2017, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance Ric Brown, during multiple gubernatorial administrations, is housed in 3 boxes. This series documents the fiscal health and credit worthiness of the Commonwealth as it pertains to obtaining and defending its bond rating. Included are meeting records between Commonwealth officials and three credit rating companies: Fitch, IBCA; Standard and Poor's; and Moody's. This series includes reports, presentations, agendas, meeting notes, and correspondence.
  - Rating Agency Briefing, 1992 Mar 26. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 1992 Sept 17. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 1994 Oct 26. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2000 June 26-27. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2000 May 28-29. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2001 Oct 18-19. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2002 May 28-29. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2003 May 13-14. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Presentation to Moody's Investors Services, Inc., 2003 Sept 26. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Arimax Presentation to Joint Meeting of House Appropriations and House Finance Committees, 2004 Feb 11. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Presentation to Standard and Poor's Ratings Service, Inc., 2004 May 21. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Presentation to Standard and Poor's, 2004 October 21. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2005 Sept 26-27. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Rating Agency Presentation (copy), 2005 Sept 26-27. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2006 June 7. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Rating Agency Presentation (copy), 2006 June 7. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2007 June 26-27. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2007 June 26-27. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Debt Capacity Advisory Committee, Report to the Governor and General Assembly, 2007 Dec 17. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 2008 Aug-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2009 Jan 9. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 2009 Feb-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Rating Agency Presentation, 2010 Jan 12. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - October Revenue Update, A Briefing for Bond Rating Firms, 2010 Nov 15. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 2011 Apr-July. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 2011 Aug. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 2012 Rating Agency Presentation, Economic Outlook and Revenue Forecast, 2012 Jan 5. (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Rating Agency Visit, 2012 Sept 27-28. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 2012 Sept. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Bond Rating Agencies, 2012 Sept 27. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Governor's Rating Agency Trip (1 of 2), 2013 Oct 3. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Governor's Rating Agency Trip (2 of 2), 2013 Oct 3. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2013 Jan-June. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2013 Oct-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2014. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Governor's Rating Agency Trip, 2015 Jan 9. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Governor's Rating Agency Trip, Supporting Documents, 2014 Nov-2015 Jan. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Update for Moody's Investors Service, 2015 Jan 16. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Call with Standard and Poor's Ratings Services, 2015 Jan 20. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Senate Finance Committee, General Government Subcommittee, 2015 Jan 27. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2015-2017. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Series III. Decision Briefs, 2014-2017., Extent: 2 boxes (2.0 cu. ft.). (Box 8-9)
  Series III. Decision Briefs, 2014-2017, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance Ric Brown, during the administration of Governor Ralph Northam, is housed in 3 boxes. This series documents the history of decision briefs sent by the staff to the Secretary of Finance or the Governor for approval. This series includes decision memoranda and supporting documentation from assigned agency heads asking the Secretary's permission to perform a major function or policy initiative within their agency. Arranged in reverse chronological order by last action taken.
  - 2017 Dec (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 2017 Dec (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 2017 Dec (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 2017 Dec (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 2017 Nov (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 2017 Oct-Nov (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 2017 Oct-Sept (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 2017 Sept (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 2017 Aug (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 2017 July (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 2017 June (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 2017 May (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 2017 Apr (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 2017 Mar (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 2017 Jan-Feb (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 2017 Jan (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 2016 Dec (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 2016 Nov (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - 2016 Sept-Oct (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 2016 Aug (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 2016 June-July (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 2016 May-June (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 2016 Mar-Apr (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 2016 Feb (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 2016 Jan (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 2015 Dec (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 2015 Sept-Nov (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 2015 Aug (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 2015 July (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 2015 June (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 2015 May (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 2015 Apr (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 2015 Jan-Mar (Box 9, Folder 15)